I'd like to introduce a representative from "Teach for America"
我想介绍一位来自"为美国而教"的代表
which is an organization that has done and is doing a lot of good,
这个组织一直致力于做好事
promoting goodness in the world and I'd like to--
在世界上宣扬善 我想…
in 1504, we've been supporting them for the last 2 years
这门课 过去两年一直向他们提供支持
and we'd like to continue to do that.
我们希望继续下去
So please.
有请
Hello. Can you hear me?
大家好 能听到吗？
Thank you so much for this.
非常感谢
I will take 90 seconds.
我只占用90秒
My name is Josh Bieber.
我叫Josh Bieber
Alright. I feel positive.
好的 我感觉很好
I was a Teacher for America Corp member and I now work for TFA.
我是为美国而教的成员 现在为组织工作
I do new site development.
负责新址开展
So when I was a senior,
大四时
I had marginally considered this is an option.
我勉强认为这是个机会
I had a napping for a very pushy phone call
招聘到期日 固执的组织招募人员
from a very pushy TFA recruiter on the deadline day--
打来电话 听电话时我差点睡着
I would not apply.
我本不会应聘
But I hesitantly took two hours to fill that essays
但我还是磨蹭了两小时完成短文
and now owe her for or owe that phone call for
多亏那个打来电话的人
the best two years of my life and truly the happiest.
这是我人生最美好 最快乐的两年
So if I have 60 seconds,
请再给我一分钟
there are just two things that I want people to know about TFA.
希望大家对组织有两个了解
I think you know what we are.
我想你们知道组织的目的
One, is that this country does not serve all kids
一是这个国家对学校里的
in our schools fairly.
孩子们的教育是不平等的
So low-income kids before they even leave elementary school
低收入孩子在离开小学前
are years behind where they should be.
已落后多年
And nearly not even a half of them graduate high school,
其中不到一半能高中毕业
which is like, a terrible injustice,
这非常不公正
a complete injustice.
完全的不公正
Two, you can actually make a difference.
二 你们能带来改变
I was as skeptical as they come about TFA
我开始也怀疑组织
and my ability and all the rest.
和自己的能力
But I know this to be true.
但我知道这是真的
If you walk into a class with 5th graders,
如果你走进一个五年级教室
who on day one are years behind where they should be
学生们从第一天开始就落后很多
and hate school and are kind of like to hate you because of it.
恨学校 因此也恨你
And nine months later,
九个月后
they leave honor above great level,
他们成绩优异
begging for some more work
恳求更多作业
and wanting to hang out with you on the weekend.
希望与你共度周未
You kinda think that anything is possible.
让你觉得一切都有可能
And that's clearly I am here now.
我在此足以说明
So for me, Teach for America is an opportunity
"为美国而教"对我来说是一个
to actually align my actions with my thoughts and my hopes
真正让我实现想法和希望的地方
and be part of the change we all talk about wanting to see.
参与实现我们都想见到的改变
So I would encourage you all,
我愿意鼓励所有同学
regardless of what you think you may do next year,
不管你们计划明年做什么
or you may go beyond that to like, really consider this.
请大家超越那些想法 考虑这个机会
It was the best thing that I could've done.
它是我可能做过的最好的事
The final deadline is tomorrow.
最后期限是明天
It's easy to do. You don't need rex.
很容易做 不需要推荐
Just apply.
申请就行
And give yourself the chance
给自己机会
to fall in love with it the way that I did.
像我一样爱上这份工作
And I will just end by saying,
最后我想说
if you are in this room right now,
现在坐在教室里的同学们
you've probably had the best education anyone your age,
可能获得同龄人中最好的教育
anywhere could possibly have.
世界上最好的教育
Our students and our schools need you.
我们的学生和学校需要你们
So please join us.
请加入我们
Thank you very much for the time.
感谢给我的时间
And have a good class.
祝大家上堂精彩的课
Hi everyone. Quickly.
大家好 只说几句
If there are any extension students or undergraduate students
如果这里有公开课学生或本科生
who were not able to make section this week,
不能在这周来上课的
we have an open section tonight at 730.
今晚七点半有一堂开放课
That'll be videotaped for the extension school.
是为公开课学员制作的录像
So if you are available and interested in attending that,
有时间和兴趣上课的
please come and see me after class.
请在课后来找我
Thanks.
谢谢
I'd like to introduce now two very dear friends
现在我想介绍两位挚友
and supporters of positive psychology
积极心理学的支持者
who are doing arguably more than anyone else
可能比任何人
to disseminate the ideas of positive psychology
更致力推广积极心理学
in a rigorous and fun way.
以严谨和有趣的方式
I've asked them to give a brief presentation
我请他们简单介绍一下
about the Masters of Applied Positive Psychology at U Penn,
宾州大学应用积极心理学硕士课程
the only master degree,
唯一的硕士学位
well the first master degree in the world--
世界上第一个硕士学位
there are a couple of others now.
目前还有其他几个
And they'll talk a little bit about--
他们会简单介绍一下
for 15 minutes-- about the masters,
利用15分钟时间 介绍一下硕士课程
before we jump into our material today,
然后再开始今天的课程
which hopefully will be exciting.
希望让人兴奋
So-- James and Debbie, please.
有请James和Debbie
Thank you very much, Tal.
非常感谢
It's great to be here with you guys.
很高兴能来到这里
What a delight to be able to spend a few minutes with you
和你们共度几分钟 真是乐事
and such a very special class,
在这样特别的课堂上
where you are combining the science of positive psychology
在这里你们将积极心理学的科学
with its practice.
和应用合二为一
And of course, as you very quickly figure out,
当然你们很快就知道
Tal is such a master teacher,
Tal是位杰出的教授
somebody who is able to take complex ideas
能把复杂的概念
and make them simple without making them simplistic
变得简单易懂 又不过份简单
and also making it inspiring
而且发人深省
and making the presentation motivating
让讲座富于感召力
so that we want to go out and apply the ideas that we are studying.
使我们想出去应用学到的理念
I'm curious-- how many of you here
我想知道有多少人
are interested in applying the science of positive psychology
对将积极心理学应用于
in your own personal life as part of why you are her.
生活中感兴趣
Can I see your hands?
请举手?
Ok. Great.
好 很好
How many of you are here because you are also
有多少人选择这门课
potentially interested in applying the science of positive psychology
是因为有兴趣在未来事业中
in your future career decisions,
应用积极心理学
in your job eventually? Ok.
在工作中? 好的
Great. Excellent.
很好 好极了
I hope you do just that.
希望你们起码能那么做
For those of you who are interested in taking positive psychology,
那些有兴趣
studies of positive psychology deeper
深入学习积极心理学的学生
at graduate level program for your own knowledge,
在研究生程度课程获取知识
but also to be able to take
但同样能够
what you are learning into your profession,
将所学带入事业
we're delighted to be able to tell you
我们很高兴能够向你们介绍
a little bit about the master of applied positive psychology program
一下宾州大学的
at the University of Pennsylvania,
积极心理学硕士课程
and to talk a little bit about taking positive psychology
谈谈将积极心理学
from the classroom to the world.
从课堂带向世界
Now as you know, positive psychology is just about 10 years old.
你们知道积极心理学刚刚诞生十年
It was started in 1998, when Martin Seligman
始于1998年 Martin Seligman
was the president of the American Psychological Association.
美国心理学协会当时的主席
And positive psychology was one of his presidential initiatives.
积极心理学是他主持开创的
About 4 years ago,
四年前
Martin Seligman started the positive psychology center
Martin Seligman创办积极心理学中心
at the University of Pennsylvania.
在宾州大学
And the mission of the positive psychology center
积极心理学中心的使命
is to promote research, training,
是推广研究 培训
education and dissemination of positive psychology.
教育和传播积极心理学
So in January, 2005,
2005年一月
I joined the positive psychology center
我加入积极心理学中心
as the director of education and senior scholar.
任教育主任和高级学者
The next month, in February of 2005,
2005年二月
Debbie Swick came on board as the associate director of education.
Debbie Swick加入中心任教育助理主任
Our task was to create a master program
我们的任务是编制硕士课程
and have an up and running by the fall.
并在秋季推出
So again, I got there in January, Debbie came in February.
我一月加入 Debbie二月加入
We got our brochure out,
三月完成论出
printed and published in March.
印刷并出版
Our application deadline was April.
申请的最后期限是四月
Kind of an optimistic, I suppose?
我猜有点乐天派
And we didn't know if anybody would show up.
我们不知道是否有人报读
We didn't know if anybody would be interested.
不知是否有人感兴趣
We needn't have worried.
但我们不需要担心
We got over 100 applications
我们收到超过一百份申请表
and we accepted 36 students into our program for that fall.
秋天时收了36名学生
And things have just been really going well and hopping ever since.
后来的收生情况越来越好
This is our current class.
这是我们当前的学生
On their first day of class in the fall of 2007,
2007年秋天 开课第一天
we have 41 students in our class this year.
今年一共收录41名学生
So I'd just like to tell you a little bit more about the students.
我想多介绍一点学生情况
Actually three of our graduates or current students
我们有三名毕业生或在读生
are teaching fellows in this class.
是这门课的助教
So that's exciting.
让人兴奋
Debbie Coen, Elizabeth Johnston-- where are you?
Debbie Coen和Elizabeth Johnston
You guys, please stand up.
请站起来
And Elizabeth Peterson. Great.
还有Elizabeth Peterson 很好
If you look at the up left corner,
看左上角
Gabriel was a student here in this class two years ago,
两年前 Gabriel修读这门课
when we came and presented on the program
在我们来推广硕士课程时
and he is currently a student in the MAPP program.
现在他正在我校读硕
So there is a lot of synergy going back and forth
这门课和我们的硕士课程
between this class and our master program.
有很多合作
Our student age range from 22 to 62.
我们的学生年纪从22岁到62岁
They come from all across United States,
来自美国各地
from Vermont to Florida, to California.
佛蒙特 弗罗里达 加州
They come from around the world:
来自世界各地
we have students from UK, from Norway,
我们的学生来自英国 挪威
Switzerland, India,
瑞士 印度
Malaysia, Japan, Hong Kong,
马来西亚 日本 香港
South Korea and New Zealand.
南韩和新西兰
About 25% to 30% of our students are younger students
25%到30%的学生是年轻人
who are just out of college
刚刚大学毕业
and are looking to immerse themselves in positive psychology
希望在进行职业训练之前
before going on into their professional training.
先深入学习积极心理学
The rest of our students are professionals
其余学生是专业人士
who come from a wide variety of professions.
来自各行各业
In our first class,
在第一班里
we had the former chief social worker inspector
学生中有来自苏格兰的
for the entire country of Scotland within the class.
全国前社工总监
That was very interesting.
那很有趣
We had kidney transplant surgeon,
肾移植医生
former Vice President of JP Morgan;
摩根大通的前副主席
we had attorneys, Directors of Development for Non-Profits;
律师 非牟利发展计划的主任
executive director of school,
学校的常务董事
Carlbrook Academy is in our class this year;
Carlbrook Academy今年选择了我们的课
human resources directors,
人力资源主管
consultants, executive coaches,
咨询师 执行教练
even professional musician and professional comedian.
甚至音乐家和喜剧演员
So it is quite a cross cut of students in the class.
班里的学生可谓五花八门
Just in a couple of minutes,
我想用两分钟
I want to give you a little bit more sense of what educational design
简单介绍一下教学设计
is and just a brief over view of the course work.
再简介一下课程内容
So this MAPP program is a one calendar year, full-time study.
本课程是一年制全日制学习
Students begin in September and end in August.
九月开始 八月毕业
The educational design is hybrid model--
我们的教育设计是混合模式
so once a month, students are on class,
每个月 学生
on site, for intensive on site classes.
有一次现场教学
And then in the intervening periods,
其余时间
they are on distant learning modules that the students complete.
学生通过远程学习模式完成
This is a professional master degree.
这是一个职业硕士学位
And it focuses on
教学重点放在
the theory and the application of positive psychology
积极心理学理论
in various professional domains.
及在各行各业的应用
So at this point,
目前来说
there is not a separate licensing or credentialing
积极心理学
in positive psychology itself.
还没有独立的执照或证书
Students come from education,
学生来自教育
business, law, medicine, etc,
商业 法律 医疗等各个领域
bringing in their own credentials with them.
都有自己的文凭
So this design of having students on campus
让学生每月来校一次
once a month for intensive classes
进行现场教学的设计
allows students to continue working full time.
允许学生继续全职工作
Now just as I said,
我刚说过
the program is full time and you may be wondering,
课程是全日制的 你可能奇怪
"How can students work full time and study full time."
"怎么可能一边工作一边全日上课"
Keep in mind this is a professional degree
请记住这是一个职业学位
and executive education model
高级管理人员教育模式
that is intended to be designed for people
就是为那些
who are themselves working full time
全职工作的人员设计的
and still taking classes full time.
同时上全制日课程
So most of our students continue their work
多数学生继续
they've been doing,
他们从事的工作
continuing working full time when they come to our class.
继续全职工作同时又能上课
Another advantage of this model
这种模式的另一个优势
is students aren't required to live in Philadelphia.
是不需要学生居住在宾州附近
Students can commute in from across United States.
学生从全国各地赶来
And what has been a surprise and pleasure to us:
即让我们惊讶且欣喜的是
students have decided to commute
远在欧洲和亚洲的学生
in from as far away as Europe and Asia.
也决定赶来
I don't know today what you commute was like to come to class.
我不知道现在你们如何来上课
But some of our students come
但我们的一些学生
as far away as South Korea and New Zealand every month
每月从南韩和新西兰赶来
to be part of the positive psychology classes.
参加积极心理学课程
So you can imagine that
可以想象
adds real excitement and energy to the class
为课堂带去的兴奋和活力
and puts a little bit pressure on the professors to make sure that
也给教授施加了压力 我们要确保
we have something worth coming half way around the world for.
能传授值得绕半个地球赶来学习的知识
This enhances the educational experience obviously
学生的多样性
by increasing student diversity:
提升了教学体验
we have students who are living abroad
居住在海外的学生
and coming in for the classes.
赶来上课
And also we are able to tap into the expertise of professors,
我们还聘请多位教授
not just at the University of Pennsylvania,
不局限于宾州大学
but also at other schools as well
还有其他大学
so that we can bring in the very top leading researchers
我们请来最杰出的研究员
and practitioners of positive psychology.
和积极心理学的从业者
A brief overview of the schedule of on-site classes on the fall 2008:
简单概述2008年秋的现场教学
you can see that there are five different intensive
春季有五个
on-site weekends in the spring
现场教学周未
as well with distant learning and intervening times.
其余时间是远程教学
So just very briefly, the courses--
简介一下课程
each student takes four courses in the fall,
每位学生秋季上四门课
four courses in the spring and then the capstone course.
春季上四门课 然后是总结性课程
In the fall,
秋季时
the courses focus on the foundational theory of positive psychology:
课程集中介绍积极心理学的基础理论
Martin Seligman teaches the Introduction
Martin Seligman教
to Positive Psychology course;
积极心理学课程概述
Angela Duckworth teaches a course on Research Methods and Evaluation
Angela Duckworth教研究手段与评估
it is very important for our students
让学生
to have a real good grasp of the science of positive psychology,
真正把握积极心理学科学很重要
understanding other research methods behind the results;
理解结论背后的研究手段
I teach a course in the foundation of positive interventions;
我教积极心理学原理
and then our fourth course is Approaches to the Good Life,
第四门课是"通向美好人生的方法"
where we have different leading researchers come in
请来多位杰出的研究人员
and talk about their research.
讨论他们的研究
In the spring, our courses focus,
春季 我们的课程
not so much on the theory,
不再以理论为焦点
but now move to the application of positive psychology
而是转向积极心理学的应用
since it's a master of applied positive psychology.
因为这是应用积极心理学硕士学位
I don't know if you study yet "the character strengths and virtues",
不知道你们是否学习了"特长与美德"
the values and the action classification by Chris Peterson.
Chris Peterson的"价值和行为分类"
If you haven't done that yet,
如果还没有学习
I'm sure you shortly will.
我肯定不久会学到
He himself comes in and teaches a course on the work he has done.
他也会教授有关自己研究的课程
I teach a course on applied positive interventions
我教积极干预应用
and we have a service learning component as a part of that class.
课程也包括一个服务教育部分
Karen Reivich and Judith Saltzberg Levick
Karen Reivich和Judith Saltzberg Levick
teach a course on positive psychology and individual--
教积极心理学和个体
so this is how to use positive psychology relationally
即在与他人的人际关系上
with other people,
如何应用积极心理学
whether it's in working environment or with friends or family.
不论是在工作中 还是与朋友家人在一起时
And then finally,
最后一门课
I don't know if you are familiar with appreciative inquiry--
不知你们是否熟习"肯定式探询"
again, I expect, if you not,
如果不知道
Tal will be introducing it to you during the course this semester
我想Tal会在本学期向大家介绍
David Cooperrider is the leader of this field of inquiry,
David Cooperrider是这个领域的先驱
which basically takes positive psychology approaches
将积极心理学方法
into organizations and seeks to foster change at the level,
带入组织 并致力寻求改变
not just individuals,
不只是个人
but at the level of the whole.
而是整体水平的改变
The final course the students take then is the Capstone project,
最后要修的一门课是总结性课程
which happens over the summer.
开课时间是夏季
This is an independent project
这是一个独立课程
where students are able to integrate
允许学生结合
what they've learned in their classes
课堂所学
and take a step forward in the directions
进一步
that they want to go in their own professional application of this.
应用于他们各自的职业
So we had students do research,
我们让学生进行研究
quantitative research or qualitative research;
量化研究和质化研究
we had students do literature reviews
我们让学生
in a particular area of interest;
就感兴趣的领域写文献观后感
work proposals for book they want to write;
他们计划写的书的进展计划
or workshop proposals and those kinds of things.
或实验计划等等
So that's a brief overview of the courses.
以上只是课程简介
Debbie is going to just take a couple of minutes
Debbie会占用几分钟时间
to show you some pictures--
给大家看一些照片
this has been a lot of texts in the last few minutes.
过去几分钟展示了太多文字
Debbie will show you some pictures and tell you more about the class.
Debbie会展示一些照片 更详细地介绍一下学生
Debbie.
交给Debbie
Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you. You heard about the course from James.
大家听过了James的课程简介
I'm going to tell you a little bit about how they are set up
我会介绍一下课程安排
and what they are.
和内容
And this is a picture from emersion week--
这是一张开学周的照片
emersion week is when the very first time students meet together
开学周时 同学初次见面
that for 5 days to Penn.
他们来宾州五天
And we have class from 8 to 5.
我们的课程从早上八点到下午五点
And I know it sounds kind of crazy
我知道听上去很疯狂
but we have a lot of fun as you can tell.
但我们相处得很快乐 你们看得出
And they stay engaged,
学生们兴趣浓厚
because we bring faculties
因为我们收录来自全球
from all over the place and this world-class faculty--
各行各业的学生 在这个世界级学院
they really have a chance to interact with these.
他们有机会进行真正的交流
The class is 41 students--
班上有41个学生
they take all the courses together
一起上课
and it's more a seminar than a lecture.
更像是论坛而非讲座
So they really get to interact quite a bit.
同学们有深入交流
And during break, during lunchtime,
休息时 午餐时
etc, they get to see these people
他们结识
that just have come in from various places.
来自世界各地的同学
Another more of interaction
宾州应用心理学硕士课程的
that you get in the MAPP program is with cohorts.
另一种交流形式是团体交流
Everyone is put in a cohort--
每个人
about 3 to 5 people.
和另外三五个人组织一个团队
And you'll do different projects with these people;
你和他们合作不同的课题
you'll do a lot of things in distant learning;
远程学习可以做很多事
you'll communicate a lot with these people.
可以经常和这些人交流
And this is just another depth that you get
这是你获得的另一种深度
when you get to work with people
当你与来自
from all different places and all different demographics.
世界各地的人合作时
And one of the things we really try to use the Capstone project for
我们很想利用总结性课程
is a stepping stone into what you are going to do
作为踏脚石 让学生
with your application.
更顺利地展开应用
And many people have taken this
很多人借助它
and they have created workshop for what they are doing.
创建工作室
One person actually took the primer in positive psychology
有一位学生把积极心理学初级课本
and she translated it into Japanese.
翻译成日语
And she's getting it published.
她的译作得以出版
And that is quite a project for her.
那个计划让她获益良多
And other people have published
还有学生
in scholarly journals their Capstone work.
在学术刊物上发表了总结性课程论文
And people give presentations and this is a photo of someone
被邀请进行讲座 这是一位学生
giving a presentation in a positive psychology summit.
在积极心理学峰会上作讲座的照片
So there are a lot of different things
我们录取学生进修硕士课程
that students do as we bring them to the program,
他们可以做各种各样的事
as we give them a solid foundation
我们给他们打下坚实基础
and then we help them start applying this move towards that.
帮助他们加以应用
But one of the biggest questions we get
申请者打来电话时
when we have applicants call in is,
询问得最多的问题是
"what can I do with a MAPP degree?"
"这个学位有什么用?"
I am going to tell you just as a quick snapshot:
我会告诉大家 这张快照上
Sasha Lewis Heinz, just the first person there--
Sasha Lewis Heinz 照片中的第一个人
she is now in the PHD program
目前她正攻读博士课程
in Development Psychology at Columbia University.
在哥伦比亚大学进修发展心理学
So she came to the MAPP program before getting her PHD.
读博前 她攻读了宾州应用心理学硕士课程
So she has that foundation
打下坚实的基础
and that's what she wants to use and focus on
那是她想应用和致力研究的
as she goes through and gets her PHD.
当她继续攻读博士时
The second person up there is Saniel Mimen
上面第二名学生是Saniel Mimen
who has worked with hedge funds but she found in her spare time--
她在投资公司工作并利用业余时间
she found some time
她挤出时间
to create a positive psychology news daily website,
创建了积极心理学每日新闻网站
which is articles about research
内容囊括宾州硕士同学会撰写的
and application of positive psychology written by MAPP alumni
有关积极心理学的研究和应用文章
who are out there actually doing that.
他们真的在进行研究和应用
And another thing she's been able to do
另外 她还和
along with a lot of other MAPP alumni
其他多名硕士同学合力
is being involved in trainings and being involved in projects
参与到培训中来 参与我们
that have come through the positive psychology center.
积极心理学中心的项目
As we get different projects to train people in the UK,
中心有各种项目 去英国培训他人
to positive psychology in their schools,
向学校推广积极心理学
the people that we draw on are MAPP alumni,
我们派去参与项目的是硕士生
because they have the education and foundation
因为他们有所需的教育背景和基础
that is needed to be able to put through these projects.
去完成这些项目
So we hope to continue
我们希望继续
to put together alumni with various opportunities
安排同学参与
that come along to us.
各种机会
Caroline Miller, the third person there--
Caroline Miller 照片中的第三个人
she is an author
她是一位作家
and she is getting ready to publish her second book
正准备出版她的第二本书
and she's also a speaker and a coach.
她也是一个演说家和教练
And she's had the opportunities
攻读硕士学位后
since MAPP to actually teach a lot of the courses
她获得很多授课的机会
and she's very focused on goal setting
她的方向是目标设立
and she's very focused on sports psychology.
和运动心理学
So this has really expanded what she's been able to do.
硕士课程大大扩展了她的能力
And not all of our students are Harvard graduates,
并非所有学生都是哈佛毕业生
but these three happened to be them. Harvard graduates.
但这三位都是哈佛毕业生
So it's very interesting to see that little snapshot.
这张快照颇有趣味
And we hope we have many more Harvard graduates coming to our program.
我们希望有更多哈佛毕业生参加我们的课程
So James, you wanna finish up here?
James 你来总结吧?
Thank you very much, Debbie.
非常感谢 Debbie
Our presentation is entitled "From the Classroom to the World".
我们的推广名为"从教室走向世界"
And certainly the MAPP program is one way
宾州应用心理学硕士课程显然是一个途径
of taking positive psychology from the classroom to the world.
将积极心理学带向世界
Just want to mention very briefly another opportunity:
再简单介绍另一个机会
We've just started the international positive psychology association.
我们刚刚创办国际积极心理学协会
And this is going to be a major international organization
它将成为一个重要国际组织
to help facilitate communication and collaboration among researchers
帮助积极心理学的研究人员和应用者
and practitioners of positive psychology.
更便利的交流与合作
Here is a picture
这是照片
that was taken at the first Board of Directors' meeting
记录了第一次董事会议
that happened in October--
在十月举行
not pictured here is Tal,
照片上没有的是Tal
who is a member of the board of the directors
他是董事会成员之一
as are a number of our other leading positive psychologists
也是美国乃至全世界
from United States and around the world.
众多杰出积极心理学家之一
There's a special student membership
协会设立特别的学生会员
so I encourage you to check out
我鼓励你们了解一下
the international positive psychology association
国际积极心理学协会
at www.ippanetwork.org
网址是www.ippanetwork.org
and join to stay abreast of the latest development
加入并把握积极心理学领域
in the field of positive psychology.
最新发展动态
I wish we had time for your questions
很希望有时间回答你们的问题
but I know Tal has a lot of great stuff for you today.
但Tal准备了很多精彩内容
So we will move along.
请继续上课
Just want to let you know that
希望大家知道
there will be an information session this afternoon,
今天下午有一个咨询会
from 3 to 4:30 in Harvard Hall, room 103.
在哈佛大厅103教室 从三点到四点半
So we'd love to see any of those of you
我们非常期待
who are interested to stop by and talk with us
有兴趣的同学过来和我们谈谈
and we'll be able to talking more detail
到时我们可以更详尽地
about more specific questions you might have at that point.
解答你们的问题
We'll also be here for a few minutes after class.
下课后 我们也会留下几分钟
We have some brochures with us.
我们带来宣传册
We'd love you to take a brochure if you are interested.
欢迎有兴趣的同学来取
There's always more information
在我们的网站上
hat can be found on our website at pennpositivepsych.org
可以了解到更多信息 pennpositivepsych.org
or you can email us the address listed.
也可向列出的地址发邮件
So we hope to see a lot of you at the MAPP program sooner or later.
希望我们能在宾州应用心理学硕士课程上见面
In the meantime,
同时
wish you have a very successful semester
祝你们本学期取得成功
as you dig into the science of positive psychology
深入学习积极心理学的科学
and put it into practice in your own lives,
并将之应用于生活
and think about how to take positive psychology
思考如何把积极心理学
from the classroom to the world.
从教室带向世界
OK.
好的
It's such a privilege to be a part of MAPP
成为宾州应用心理学硕士班的一员是种特权
because what you have there in a year
因为在那里共度一年的
is all the top people from the field.
是来自各个领域的杰出人物
So many of the people we'll talk about,
我们将会谈到的很多人
whether it's Bob Fredrickson who we'll talk about in a few minutes,
比如Bob Fredrickson 过一会我们会谈到他
whether it's David Cooper we'll talk about,
或者以后会谈到的David Cooper
whether it's Martin Seligman of course,
当然还有Martin Seligman
will come there and present to you
都会去那里给大家讲座
and you'll be spending quality time in small groups with them.
你将和他们亲密相处
Real privilege.
真是一种特权
So what I want to do today is finish up on the basic premises,
今天我想结束有关基础前提的讨论
on the final premise.
讨论最后一个前提
Now we are going to watch it again. No?
还要再看这个吗 不
Or that?
这个也不用看了
Here we go.
可以了
The final and the fifth premise is an important one;
最后也是第五个前提很重要
is a philosophical one
是一个哲学前提
but one I want to introduce at the beginning of the course
但我想在课程开始时介绍
so that you understand where I am coming from,
你们好理解我讲课的起源
where this course is coming from--
这门课程的来源
because many people say,
因为很多人说
"Ok, so happiness is important.
好的 快乐是重要的
We seek it; we have declarations--
我们寻找它 我们有宣言
national declarations,
国家宣言
individual declarations of how important it is for us.
关于快乐对我们多么重要的个人宣言
But that doesn't mean that it is important or the "is",
但那不代表它是重要的 问题在于这个"是"
the fact that it is important doesn't mean we ought to do it.
它是重要的但不代表我们应该去做
My argument here is that not only is it important,
我认为它不仅重要
it also ought to be important.
而且也应该是重要
So first about the "is".
首先要阐述这个"是"
Happiness, whether we like it or not,
快乐 不论我们喜欢与否
whether it's consciously ,
不论它是有意识地
subconsciously, whether it's explicit or implicit,
还是潜意识地 不论它是明显的还是隐晦的
for most people--
对多数人来说
not all, but for most people,
不是全部但对多数人来说
it is the highest end.
快乐是最高追求
And again, we have Constitution save God in our pursuit of happiness.
我们有宪法保证我们追求快乐
We spend a lot of effort,
我们投入大量努力
a lot of time thinking about it for ourselves as well as for others.
大量时间思考自己和他人的快乐
Aristotle, over 2000 years ago,
二千多年前的亚里斯多德
"Happiness is the meaning and purpose of life,
"快乐是人生的意义和目的
the whole aim and end of human existence."
人类存在的最终目标"
William James
in 1890 or in "The Variety of Religious Experiences" writes, "
1890年在"宗教经验之种种"中写道
If we were to ask the question:
如果要问
"What is human life's chief concern?"
人类生命最主要的担心是什么?
one of the answers we should receive would be:
我们应该得到的一个答案是
"It is happiness."
"是快乐"
How to gain, how to keep,
如何获得 如何保持
how to recover happiness,
如何重获快乐
is in fact for most men at all times the secret motive of all they do,
是多数人时刻怀有的秘密动机
and all they are willing to endure."
是他们愿意忍受一切的目的
Now you may have heard of William James--
你们可能听说过William James
his name is after the building here.
这里有幢大楼以他命名
And he talked about this over 200 years ago;
他在二百多年前谈到快乐
Aristotle over 2000 years ago.
亚里斯多德在二千多年前也谈过
And it's not just peculiar to the West.
而且不只是西方人
The Dalai Lama, "Whether one believes in a religion or not,
达赖喇嘛 "不论一个人是否相信宗教
whether one believes in this religion or that religion,
不论一个人相信这种还是那种宗教
the very purpose of our life is happiness.
我们生命的最终目标是快乐
The very motion of our life is towards happiness."
我们生命的主要活动是寻找快乐"
So it is important for people.
快乐是重要的
Again, whether it's conscious,
不论是有意识的
subconscious, explicit or implicit,
还是潜意识的 明显的还是隐晦的
the question though is in fact it is important,
问题是它确实重要
should it be important?
但快乐应该是重要的吗？
What about the moral dimension of happiness?
快乐的道德维度呢？
There are so many other things happening,
还有很多事情在发生
so many important things to do in the world.
世上有很多重要的事情要做
Why should we have happiness as our highest end,
为什么把快乐作为最终目标
as our chief concern,
作为主要担心
as that which determines the motion of our life?
为什么由它来决定生命活动？
In other words, what's good about wellbeing?
换言之 幸福有什么好处？
What's good about positive emotions?
积极情绪有什么好处？
And there is a lot of research to answer this question.
大量研究都尝试回答这个问题
But before the research,
暂不说研究
it feels good to feel good.
感觉好就是感觉好
Think about it. Internalize it.
想到快乐 注入内心
This is Aristotle's Law of Identity:
这是亚里斯多德的"同一律"
A is A-- it feels good to feel good.
一即一 感觉好就是感觉好
And that, in and of itself is justification:
这本身就是辩解理由
why not feel good, if we can feel good?
如果能感觉好 为什么不感觉好呢?
So the burden to prove
证明
why happiness is not important may be on the people
快乐为什么是不重要的重担可能落在
who would argue otherwise--
执否定观点的人身上
we will talk about that argument later.
我们会在以后谈到这个论点
But the first key issue is that it's good in and of itself--
但首先的关键问题是快乐本身是好的
almost needs no justification.
几乎无需辩解
However, beyond just feeling good,
然而除了感觉好
happiness also contributes to our life,
快乐还对我们的人生有帮助
to our relationships.
对人际关系有帮助
It contributes to other people.
对他人有帮助
This is research done by Barbara Fredrickson,
Barbara Fredrickson做了这项研究
one of the faculty members who teaches at U PENN.
在宾州大学任教的学会成员
You saw a picture of her up there.
你们曾在上面见过她的照片
What Barbara Fredrickson says is that
Barbara Fredrickson的观点是
positive emotions have an evolutionary reason,
积极情绪有一个进化理由
that they have a purpose beyond just making us feel good.
它们的目的不仅仅是让人感觉好
For example, they help us think beyond
比如它们有助我们超越
what we are thinking right now, broaden our thinking;
现在的思考范畴 拓展我们的思想
they help us build relationships;
有助我们建立人际关系
they help us build capacities--
帮助我们建立能力
remember one of the key concepts of this course
这门课的一个主要概念
is the positive emotions,
就是积极情绪
positive psychology as a field as a whole,
积极心理学
is about building capacities.
就是要建立能力
The two analogies we use
我们使用的两个类比
was strengthening our immune system or stronger "psychological engine"
是加强我们的免役系统或加强"心理引擎"
that has the capacity to endure more
获得更强大的忍受能力
not just from the negative to zero,
不只是从负到零
but also from the zero to the positive.
还要从零到正
So this is Barbara Fredrickson.
这是Barbara Fredrickson的观点
Let me quote extensively from her article,
我想进一步引用她的文章
which I believe you are reading for this week,
也是你们这周要阅读的
"We should work to cultivate positive emotions
"我们应该努力培育积极情绪
in ourselves and in those around us,
在自己身上和周围人身上
not just as end states in themselves,
不能只将它们作为终极状态
but also as a means to achieving psychological growth
还要将其作为手段实现心理成长
and improved psychological and physical health over time.
改善心理和身体的健康
I call this the broaden-and-build theory of positive emotions
我称其为积极情绪的扩建理论
because positive emotions appear to broaden people's momentary thought
因为积极情绪似乎能扩展人们的瞬间想法
action repertoire and build the enduring personal resources.
和动作指令库并建立持久的个人资源
Through experiences of positive emotions,
通过体验积极情绪
people transform themselves,
人们实现改变
becoming more creative, knowledgeable,
变得更有创造力 更博学
resilient, socially integrated,
适应性更强 更易融入社会
and healthy individuals."
获得更健康的人格"
Numerous benefits to just experiencing positive emotions.
体验积极情绪有诸多好处
It's a win-win.
是双赢的
It feels good.
它让人感觉好
And it's good for us and it's good for society as a whole
对我们有好处 对整个社会也有好处
as I'll argue momentarily.
一会我就会解释
So what she's talking about here, for example,
她谈到的问题包括
is that positive emotions help us overcome negative emotions.
积极情绪有助我们克服消极情绪
What happens when we experience negative emotions
体验消极情绪时
is that our consciousness,
我们的意识
our thinking narrows and constricts.
我们的思维变得狭窄 收紧
We focus just on one thing, so for example.
只专注于一件事 比如
And that can be a good thing--
那可能是件好事
you know, a lion comes to and charges me,
一头狮子朝我冲过来
"I don't want to start thinking about my MAPP application.
我不想考虑宾州大学硕士申请的事
I don't want to start thinking about what my roommates say.
不想考虑室友说了什么
I want to focus on the lion.
我只想考虑这头狮子
So my consciousness narrows and constricts,
我的意识变得狭窄 收紧
and I'm in the "fight or flight" mode.
进入"对抗或逃跑"模式
Now that's a good thing when a lion charges me.
有狮子朝我冲来时是件好事
But it's not a very good thing
但它变得不是很好
if my consciousness continues to narrow
如果我的意识继续狭窄
and constrict beyond the threat, or beyond the hardship.
收紧超出威胁 超出困难
And what we know is that very often we enter a downward spiral,
我们知道经常会进入下行螺旋
a vicious cycle when we go into this narrow and constrict mode.
一个恶性循环 当我们进入狭窄收紧的模式
So for example, just for example-- a random example:
随便举个例子
My girlfriend leaves me, alright?
女朋友离开了我
And I narrow and constrict in terms of my thinking--
我的思维收窄缩紧
all I am thinking about is just that.
一心只想着被女友甩了
And what will happen is as a result,
结果就是
I experience sadness,
我感觉悲伤
because that is what I am thinking about, and sadness--
因为我一心只想那个 悲伤
a painful emotion, not a positive emotion--
是一种痛苦的情绪 一种消极情绪
leads to further narrow and constrict.
导致进一步的收窄缩紧
And that can potentially,
那有可能
not always, but potentially can go on and on and on.
并非总是 但可能一直持续下去
And that's when it can become depression.
直到变成抑郁
That's when I have difficulty getting out of this downward,
那时我将很难脱离这种下行
vicious cycle.
恶性的循环
Positive emotions do the opposite.
积极情绪正相反
They broaden and build.
它们扩展建立
Broaden and build leads to positive emotions.
扩建导致积极情绪
Then positive emotions further broaden and build.
积极情绪再进一步扩建
So that's a virtuous cycle.
所以是个良性循环
And I look broadly,
我眼界宽了
I look to othe people,
关注其他人
I look to other things: So what can I do now?
关注其他事 思考现在我能做什么?
Where can I go? Where can I spend my time?
我能去哪里?我把时间用在哪里?
And very often what that does--
很经常的是
a positive emotion can take us out of this downward spiral
积极情绪把我们带出下行螺旋
and create an upward spiral.
形成一个上行螺旋
A positive emotion can come in form of watching a humorous film;
积极情绪可以是看一部滑稽电影
it can come in form of "if you take a deep breath"--
可以是"一次深呼吸"
we talked about deep breathing when we talked about my body;
探讨"心理 身体"时会谈到深呼吸
a positive emotion can come in form of interaction with a friend,
积极情绪可以是与朋友交流
a pleasant one.
一次愉快的交流
It's the positive emotion
积极情绪
that can take us out from this downward spiral to this upward spiral.
能把我们带离这个下行螺旋进入这个上行螺旋
And again it doesn't always take a very long time.
而且不用很久
And the challenge is to combine "the permission to be human"
困难在于将之与准许为人相结合
to experience the emotion to go through the motion
去体会情绪 实现转移
and yet not to enter the downward spiral where six months later,
但不会进入下行螺旋
after small incident, I'm still in that rot.
在发生小小意外六个月后 仍心情低落
We'll talk about what is the right time
我们会谈到什么是合适的时候
and how do you find the right time,
如何找到合适的时候
how do you find the balance
以及如何在
between thinking about painful emotions
思考痛苦情绪
and when does it slide to rumination,
和让痛苦情绪滑入沉思到平衡
which is not always helpful.
沉思并非总有帮助
So it helps overcome the negative emotions.
它有助克服消极情绪
Also, creativity-- we think broadly--
还有创造力 我们的眼界更宽
we are able to make connections,
能产生更多联系
see connections we haven't seen before, perhaps.
看到以前没有看到的联系
There's a lot of the talk about the depressive creature.
有很多关于"抑郁创造者"的说法
If you want to have high level of creativity,
如果你想拥有更高水平的创造力
it's a must you have to be depressed.
必须承受抑郁
Well, it turns out that's not the case.
其实并非如此
Very often manic depressives are highly creative,
躁狂抑郁病人一般更有创造力
but that's usually during their manic phases.
但一般在躁狂阶段
In the depressed phase, our thinking is narrow;
在抑郁阶段 我们的思维收窄
we don't think outside the box usually--
我们失去创造力
of course there's many exceptions, but as a whole.
当然有例外 但总体而言没有
In fact there's research--
实际上有这样一项研究
for example, this was done with internists, doctors,
在内科医生 医生中间进行
who are giving a very difficult,
向他们提出一个
very difficult question connected to a liver problem
与肝脏问题有关的很困难的问题
that an individual patient had.
那是一个病人的病症
And they divided them randomly into three groups--
医生们被随机分成三组
the first group was a control group--
第一组是对照组
they just had to solve the problem;
他们必须解决这个问题
the second group was given a statement
第二组听一段有关
about humanistic value of medicine--
医学人文观的声明
why is it so important to be a medical doctor;
为什么作医生如此重要
and the third group was given candy
第三组得到糖果
and put in a funny playful good mood.
让他们获得愉快放松的好心情
The third group that was given the candies
第三组得到糖果
and put in a positive playful mood
并获得积极愉快的心情
outperformed the other two groups significantly--
明显比另外两组有更好表现
they thought about more options
他们考虑更多选择
and they actually came up with better solutions with that problem.
得出更好的问题解决办法
And this is one of many studies in this area.
这是这个领域中的一项研究
Another example-- children.
再举个例子 小孩子
One group of children was a control group;
一群小孩组成对照组
the second group was taught to think back
有人教第二组小孩回想
to experience that make them laugh or smile.
让他们大笑或微笑的经历
And that group did much better
第二组
on the learning task than the control group,
在学习任务上比对照组表现更好
because they were put into a positive mood.
因为他们被置于积极情绪
Again, it's a win-win.
它是双赢的
It's defined in many ways that "no pain, no gain" paradigm,
它在很多方面定义了"没有痛苦就没有回报"
whether it's education of doctors or in school,
不论是对医生的教育还是在学校
as well as generally in the workplace.
在一般的工作场所也一样
Because you see, also motivation and energy--
因为动力和精力
you don't need research for that,
不需要研究就能明白
you know that when you are feeling good,
你知道感觉好时
you have more motivation, you have more energy--
动力和精力更充沛
of course, there is a lot of research to back that up.
当然有很多研究支持这一点
And ultimately success.
最终达到成功
They look in the professional people
他们调查专业人士
who are able to manage their emotions
能更好地控制自己的情绪
better and lead to positive emotions,
获得积极情绪
get out of this narrow and constrict to the broaden and build
脱离狭窄收紧进入扩建的人
are in the long term more successful.
长远会取得更大成功
Again, it's not that people who don't have painful emotions--
他们不是没有痛苦情绪
remember? They are all dead.
没有的都是死人
It's that people who experience painful emotions
那些人经历痛苦情绪
but are all in the same time able to shift themselves,
但同时能够更好地
their consciousness, their thinking,
把自己 他们的意识 思想
their experience to the positive more readily.
他们的感受向积极方向转移
And happier people are more successful,
越快乐的人越成功
because they have more energy and work harder.
因为他们有更多精力 工作更努力
It's because their pursuing something
因为他们在追求
rather than running away from something--
而不是在逃离
it is called "approach rather than avoidance goals"--
这叫"靠近而非逃避目标"
we'll talk about that during the week on goals.
我们将在探讨"目标"时谈到
Also because they form better relationships.
还因为他们建立更好的人际关系
They are more open and generous.
他们更开放更宽容
And they are more creative.
他们的创造力更强
All these components ultimately lead to higher levels of success.
所有这些因素最终导致更高层次的成功
Positive emotions not only contribute to our success,
积极情绪不仅有助成功
they don't just contribute to our feeling good,
不仅能让我们感觉好
they also contribute to our wellbeing.
还有助我们获得幸福
Optimistic people, and again,
乐观的人
not Pollyannaish detached optimism,
不是指盲目的乐天派
but grounded optimists,
而是脚踏实地的乐观主义者
on average, live significantly longer.
平均而言 明显更加长寿
Bless you.
保佑你们
The immune system is stronger,
免疫系统更强
so it also helps in terms of physical health.
所以对身体健康也有帮助
But now the question is the moral question:
现在的问题是 道德问题
What about other people?
那么其他人呢?
How can I talk about or act in my life,
我谈论经营自己的生活
pursuing my happiness isn't that selfish?
追求自己的快乐 这怎么不是自私?
Ant the answer is: "Yes, it is selfish."
答案是"是的 那是自私"
When I talk to myself, when I say to myself,
当我对自己说
"I want to be happier",
"我想更快乐"
I say to myself, "I want to be happier."
我对自己说"我想更快乐"
That' s a selfish thing.
那是一件自私的事
So it that bad? Is that immoral?
它是坏的吗?是不道德的吗?
Well, in our culture,
在我们的文化中
selfishness and immorality have essentially become synonymous.
自私和不道德成了同义词
And that's a problem.
那是个问题
And here's why. Because this is the No. 1--
这就是为什么 因为这是头号
equating to selfishness and immorality is the No. 1 cause--
将自私等同于不道德是头号原因
subconsciously mostly, but not only--
多数是在潜意识里
No. 1 cause of unhappiness.
导致不快乐的头号原因
Because people feel guilty about pursuing their own happiness.
人们为追求自己的快乐感到内疚
People feel guilty at times feeling good about themselves.
人们在自我感觉很好时会内疚
How can I? How dare I feel good about myself?
我怎么可以? 我怎么敢自我感觉良好?
How can I pursue my happiness
我怎么能追求自己的快乐
when there is so much suffering in the world?
当世上有那么多痛苦时?
And there is a lot of suffering in the world.
世上确有很多痛苦
So how do we respond to that?
我们要如何回应?
First of all, happiness is a positive sum game--
首先 快乐是正和博弈
it's not a zero sum game.
不是零和博弈
Neither it is a negative sum game--
也不是负和博弈
it's not that my happiness takes away from other people's happiness
我的快乐不是从别人那里夺来
which will be a negative sum game:
那将是负和博弈
if I have more, you'll necessarily have less.
我有更多 你一定更少
It's not even a zero--
甚至不是一个零…
or rather if I have less,
或者我更少
you'll have less- that's a negative sum game--
你也会更少 那也是负和博弈
or a zero sum game-- if I have more, you'll have less-
或零和博弈 我更多 你就会更少
it's a fixed pie.
饼就那么大
It's not that.
不是这样的
It's a positive sum game.
它是一个正和博弈
Why? Because happiness is contagious.
为什么?因为快乐是感染的
If I'm happier, I'm more likely
如果我更快乐 我更有可能
to contribute to other people's happiness and wellbeing.
对他人的快乐和幸福作出贡献
Being happy, in other words,
感受快乐 换言之
is also a moral state in the sense of actually contributing
也是一种道德状态
to other people's wellbeing.
对他人的幸福作出贡献
The Buddha talked about it thousands of years ago,
佛在几千年前就谈到它
"Thousands of candles can be lit from a single candle,
"一支蜡烛可以点燃千支蜡烛
and the life of the candle will not be shortened.
蜡烛的生命不会被缩短
Happiness never decreases by being shared."
分享绝不会减少快乐"
It's like passing on light.
就像传递光明
If you are happy, and work on your happiness,
你快乐并努力争取快乐
you are contributing indirectly to other people's happiness,
就是间直接对他人的快乐作出贡献
just like the baby who laughed last time-- made you laugh.
就像上次大笑的婴儿 把你们逗笑
It's contagious.
笑是感染的
Generally people who work on their happiness--
一般来说 努力争取快乐的人
again, not people who experience constantly high,
再一次 不是那些总是保持快乐的人
they would have difficulty having real relationships
那种人将很难建立人际关系
since they are dead--
因为他们是死的
but generally, people, those of us who are alive,
一般来说 活着的人
who work on happiness,
努力争取快乐
who experience the vicissitude of life-- the ups and downs--
体验生活的变迁 起起落落
but overall work on happiness and become happier and happier,
但努力争取快乐而且越来越快乐
have better relationships,
有更好的人际关系
more generous, more accepting of other people,
更宽容 更接受他人
more tolerant of other people as well as themselves.
更容忍他人和他们自己
There's a lot of research to show that helping ourselves,
很多研究表明自我帮助
in other words, working on our happiness,
换言之 努力为自己争取快乐
contributing to our wellbeing,
有助我们获得幸福
leads us to also be more generous and benevolent toward others.
也能引导我们对他人更加宽容和亲切
This is a research by one of the leading researchers,
一位重要的研究者
one of the first researches in the area of positive emotions,
积极情绪领域的首批研究者之一
Alice Isen.
Alice Isen进行了这个研究
And she showed, time and again,
她反复证明
how feeling good is good for us and good for others,
感觉好如何对我们和他人都有益
and it works the other way as well.
反之亦然
This is a wonderful thing about happiness.
这是快乐很美妙的地方
It works the other way as well,
别人快乐你也快乐
because helping others also helps ourselves.
因为帮助他人也是帮助自己
Remember your task for this week--
记得你们这周的任务
a dozen of you have already read it--
一些同学已经知道
it's to commit- above and beyond what you usually commit-
就是去做超越以往所做的事情
five extra acts of kindness during one day.
一天内多做五件好事
Five extra acts of kindness.
多做五件好事
This is a research done by Sonja Lyubomirsky--
这是Sonja Lyubomirsky做过的一项研究
I mentioned her book in the first class:
我在第一堂课提及她的书
"The how of happiness".
《快乐之道》
She's done fantastic work,
她很好地
showing how people who help--
证明人们
whether it's helping five extra acts during the week--
不论是在一周内多做五件好事
it can be more;
可以更多
doesn't have to be restricted to five--
不必局限于五件
or people who help five extra acts during one day,
或者人们在一天内多做五件好事
it's actually contributing to their wellbeing.
都能让他们更幸福
So helping others is also helping ourselves.
帮助他人也是帮助自己
You know, one of the things that I say and only half ingest,
我说到的一件事 只说了一半意思
is that I know of no more selfish act and a benevolent act.
即最自私的所为就是善举
Again, only half ingest--
只说了一半意思
because the two are interconnected.
因为两者有内在联系
And there is a self-enforcing loop between the two,
两者间有自我实施的循环
where helping others helps ourselves;
帮助他人就是帮助自己
and helping ourselves, in turn, helps others.
帮助自己继而帮助他人
And rather than looking it as selfish--
不要把它看作自私
some people may feel this ease way--
有人可能会这样简单考虑
and rather than looking it as selfish i.e. -- equal immoral.
不该把自私等同于不道德
We should look at it as something
我们应该把它视为
that is so wonderful about our nature,
人性的美妙之处
a part of our nature that we should celebrate.
是我们应该颂扬的本性
The fact that our happiness is tied to others,
我们的快乐与他人的相关连
the fact that we are tied to others in a web of empathy--
我们通过同情网络和他人相关连
that's a wonderful thing about human nature.
那是人性的美妙之处
A thing that we need to celebrate much more than we are doing already.
一样值得我们进一步颂扬的东西
Because remember, if we don't celebrate,
如果不颂场
if we don't appreciate that part of our nature,
如果我们不欣赏人性的那一部分
that part of our nature will depreciate.
人性的那一部分将贬值
To appreciate has two meanings as we talked about:
欣赏有两个意思
one is to say "thank you" for something and two is to grow.
一是懂得感谢 二是传递
If we appreciate the good in our nature,
如果我们欣赏人性中
in our inclinations,
欲望中好的东西
if we appreciate that part of our nature,
如果我们欣赏本性中那一部分
it will appreciate and we'll have more of it.
它将升值 我们将获得更多
If we look down at it and say,
如果我鄙视它并说
"It's a terrible thing that
"很可怕
I just derive benefits from helping other people",
我从帮助他人身上获得利益"
then that part of our nature will depreciate over time.
那么本性中那一部分将随时间贬值
For your readings, you are reading one of the meditations in my book,
你们正在读我书中的冥想部分
where I talk about it a little bit more in length,
书中有更详细的阐述
and I also gave the philosophical foundation,
也给出了哲学基础
because in many ways this goes against "counting and thinking"
因为在很多方面有别于"数数和思考"
that has been so dominant in our 20th and 21st century
那种方法在20和21世纪处于统治地位
thinking about morality.
思考道德
It feels good to feel good.
感谢好就是感觉好
It also contributes to others to feel good.
也能让他人感觉好
I want to end this premise idea
我想以介绍一位
by talking a little bit about a person for whom,
一生致力于
one of the chief purpose in life was to spread happiness--
传播快乐的人来结论这个前提
Mahatma Gandhi. This is a story about him.
圣雄甘地 这是关于他的一个故事
There was a woman like many people came
一个女人像很多人一样
to ask for advice from Gandhi.
来寻求甘地的建议
And she came from very far away.
她长途赶来
And she brought her son along.
还带着儿子
And she said in front-- she got audience with Mahatma,
她拜见甘地
and she said in front of him, and she said to him
在他面前说 她对他说
"I came from afar, because I have a problem with my son.
"我长途赶来 因为我儿子有个问题
My son eats way too much sugar.
我儿子吃太多糖
And I'd like you to tell him to stop it.
希望你能告诉他别吃太多糖
Because it's hurting his health, his teeth.
因为糖损害他的健康 牙齿
And he will listen to you. He admires you.
他会听你的 他很崇拜你"
" Gandhi looked at her and said,
甘地看着她说
"Madam, can you please come back in a month?"
"夫人 你能一个月后再来吗?"
She didn't know why but she listened to him after all--
她不明白为什么但还是听了他的话
he was Gandhi.
因为他是甘地
She left, went far away,
她离开 长途返回
came all the way back a month later,
一个月后又回来
and once again, got an audience with Gandhi.
再次与甘地见面
She said in front of him,
她在他面前说
She said "I was here a month ago."
她说"一个月前我来过"
And he said, "Yes. I remember."
他说"是的 我记得"
And she said, "Could you please tell my son
她说"你能告诉我儿子
to stop eating so much sugar?"
不要吃太多糖吗?"
So Gandhi looks at the child intensely and says,
于是甘地注视着那个孩子说
"Son, stop eating too much sugar."
"孩子 不要再吃太多糖"
And that's it.
就是这样
The woman is obviously perplexed and musters up her courage,
那个女人很困惑 她鼓起勇气
and says, "Mahatma, thank you very much.
说"圣雄 非常感谢
I'm sure he will stop eating too much sugar,
我肯定他不会再吃太多糖
but why couldn't you tell him this a month ago,
但为什么不在一个月前告诉他
when I came all the way here?"
在我长途赶来的时候?"
And he said, "Well, madam, because a month ago,
他说"夫人 因为一个月前
I was eating too much sugar."
我也吃太多糖"
Yeah, I know, it's a very sophisticated joke--
是的 我知道这是个很深奥的笑话
it takes a while, but I'm glad you got it.
需要时间 很高兴你们消化了
One of the things Gandhi said,
甘地说过一件事
that he talked about is from his wonderful autobiography,
出自他的精彩自传
"My experiment with truth"--
《我的对于真理的实践经历》
"Be the change you want to see in the world."
"成为你想在世上见到的改变"
This is how you bring about change.
只有这样才能实现改变
I want to do a quick exercise with you.
我和想大家作个小练习
This is a tough exercise especially for guys,
特别对男生来说是个困难练习
but please bear with me.
但请忍耐
So-- if you don't feel comfortable doing it,
感觉不舒服的
don't do it-- what I'd like to do now is as following:
就不要做 希望按下面的指示做
Take your thumb and your middle finger
让你的姆指和中指
and create as much as possible a 90 degree angle.
尽可能形成一个直角
May hurt a little bit,
可能有点痛
but try as much as possible to create a 90 degree angle.
尽可能形成一个直角
Ok, watch me: Just like this, Ok?
看着我 就像这样
90 degree angle.
直角
Now take these two fingers--
再让这两个手指
the middle finger and the thumb--
中指和姆指
and as much as possible, from that 90 degree angle, create a circle.
尽可能保持直角时围成一个圆圈
Again, it's more difficult for men than for women--
男性比女性更难做到
less flexible.
男性的柔韧度更小
Create a circle.
围成一个圆圈
So it looks like a rabbit.
看上去像只兔子
If you have them on the show.
如果能投影的话
Middle finger exactly and your thumb.
中指和姆指
Alright, just watch me.
好 看着我
Like this. As much as possible.
像这样 尽可能围成一个圆圈
It's not perfectly round, but as much as possible.
不是完美的圆但要尽力
Now take that circle that you have just created--
把这个围起来的圆圈
Can you see? That's a circle.
看到吗? 这是个圆圈
Take that circle and put it on your cheek.
把这个圆圈放在面颊上
Your other cheek.
另一个地方
Ok, this could also take a while.
可能需要一会
But most people from what I see, put it on their chin.
我看到的多数同学都放在了下巴上
Now I said it very clearly, "cheek".
我很清楚地说是"面颊"
But you see, here is the thing:
问题就在这里
People mostly do what you do, rather than what you say.
多数人都是照你做的做而不是照你说的做
So remember that,
请记住这一点
because I don't think there is anyone in this room
我不认为课堂上有任何人
who would tell me now,
会告诉我
"my goal in life, my objective is to make people miserable.
"我的人生目标是让别人不幸
I really want to do that.
我真得想那么做
You know I want everyone to be miserable in the world."
我想要世上所有人都不幸"
There is not one person here who would actually say that, I hope.
这里不会有人真得说出那种话 希望如此
So most of us here, whatever we do in our lives,
我们在座的多数人 不论做什么
now and in the future, are idealists.
从现在到未来 都是理想主义者
We want to do good in the world;
我们想为世人造福
we want to spread happiness.
想传播快乐
But remember, people do what you do,
但记住 人们照你做的做
not what you say.
不是照你说得做
So you may want to spread happiness, through your word.
你也许想传播快乐 通过你的言话
But ultimately, the best way,
但最好的方法
the optimal way spreading happiness is to work on your own happiness,
传播快乐的最佳方法是努力争取自己的快乐
because then you are leading by example.
因为那时你就成为榜样
That applies to leadership.
这也适用于领导
The most important thing about leadership is not what you say;
领导最重要的不是说的话
it's what you do.
而是如何以身作则
The most important thing about parenting--
为人父母最重要的
it's not how much you tell your child "honesty is important"
不是告诉子女"诚实很重要"
but rather how honest you are.
而是你自身有多诚实
If you want to spread happiness,
如果你想传播快乐
"Be the change you want to see in the world." By example.
"成为你想在世上见到的改变" 以身作则
So these are the five basic premises that we talked about.
这就是五个基本前提
They formed the foundation of the course.
它们构成这门课的基础
And what we are going to do over the next couple of month
我们将在未来两个月
is expand on these--
扩展这些前提
most importantly, see how we can take the research,
最重要的是如何将研究
the rigor and apply it to our lives.
原则运用于生活
So let me move on now to the next lecture,
现在开始下一课
which is "Belief as Self-Fulfilling Prophecies".
"信念即自我实现预言"
This I must say,
我必须承认
this topic ignited my imagination
这个话题点燃了我的想象
when I was a kid when I thought about it;
当我是孩子时想到它
when I was an athlete.
当我还是一名运动员时
And that's when I understood the power of the mind.
那时我明白了信念的力量
And that would pick my interests in psychology.
后来它挑起我对心理学的兴趣
I want to start with a story, a specific story,
我想从一个特别的故事开始
that in many ways I can say it is the first story,
在很多方面 它是我听到过的
psychological story that I heard of.
第一个有关心理学的故事
The story that I heard that brought home to me the message
那个故事让我明白
how important psychology is to wellbeing and to success.
心理学对幸福和成功是多么重要
And success, as a fourteen years-old squash player,
成功对14岁的壁球手来说
was the most important thing in my life.
是我生命中最重要的东西
And the story is of Roger Bannister.
故事讲的是Roger Bannister
Just so I get a show of hands:
举下手
how many people have heard of Roger Bannister? Ok. A handful.
多少人听说过他?好的 只有少数
So those of you who have, can hear it again.
听过的可以重温一次
Roger Bannister was a runner.
Roger Bannister是个跑手
He ran the mile.
跑一英里
And until 1954, running the mile in under 4 minutes
直到1954年 在四分钟以内跑完一英里
was considered impossible.
被认为是不可能的
In fact, doctors proved the 4 minutes for the mile
事实上医生证明四分钟跑一英里
was the limit of human ability.
是人类能力的极限
Physiologists ran tests,
生理学家进行实验
showing, proving scientifically the limit of human ability
在科学上展示证明人类能力极限
was running the mile in 4 minutes.
是四分钟跑一英里
You could not go below that.
不可能少于四分钟
And runners proved the doctors and scientists--
跑手们证明了医生和科学家…
proved that they were right
证明了他们是对的
and ran the mile in two seconds and 4 minutes,
一英里跑四分钟两秒
one second, but no runner could run the mile in under 4 minutes,
四分钟一秒 但没有跑手能少于四分钟
ever since the mile was actually timed--
从一英里跑计时以来
when they started to time runs.
当人们开始计时跑时
It was impossible-- doctors and scientists showed,
那是不可能的 医生和科学家证明了
runners, athletes,
跑手 运动员
the top-ones in the world proved that the doctors were right.
世上顶尖选手证明了医生们是对的
And then came along Roger Bannister.
然后Roger Bannister出现
Roger Bannister said, "It is possible to run in 4 minutes.
他说"四分钟内跑完是可能的
And in fact, I'm going to do it."
我要做给你们看"
Now when he said it, he was a medical doctor at Oxford University.
说这话时 他是牛津大学的医学博士
He was a good runner,
也是一名出色的跑手
top runner, but nowhere near the 4 minutes mark.
顶级跑手 但时间远高于四分钟
His best time was 4 minutes and 12 seconds.
他的最好时间是四分12秒
And of course, no one took him seriously.
自然没有人把他当真
But Roger Bannister continued to train and work hard,
但Roger Bannister坚持苦练
not harder than the rest of the runners,
不比别的跑手练得更苦
but as hard as the top runners in the world.
但和世上别的跑手一样苦练
And he did get better.
而且有进步
In fact, he broke the 4 minutes and 10 seconds mark,
他突破了四分十秒
4 minutes and 5 seconds mark
四分五秒
and he got 4 minutes and 2 seconds and stopped,
跑到四分两秒时停止
like everyone else--
像所有人一样
could not go below the 4 minutes and 2 seconds.
无法低于四分二秒
So he wasn't even the best runner in the world,
他不是世上最好的跑手
but among the best.
但也是佼佼者
But he continued to say "it is possible;
但他还是说"有可能
there is no human limitation on that;
在这件事上人类没有极限
we can run the mile in under 4 minutes."
我们能在四分钟之内跑完一英里"
And he continued to say, continued to train for years.
他坚持这么做 坚持练习 却一直失败
Until 1954. On the 6th of May, 1954,
直到1954年 1954年5月6日
on his home tour at Oxford University,
在重回故校时
Roger Bannister ran the mile in 3 minutes and 59 seconds.
Roger Bannister用了3分59秒跑完一英里
Sensation. Front page news all over the world.
轰动一时 登上全世界的头版头条
"Science defied". "Doctors defied".
"科学遭到挑战""医生遭到挑战"
"The impossible made possible".
"不可能成为可能"
It became known as the dream mile.
它成为梦想一英里
Now listen to this.
现在听这个
For decades, ever since the mile was timed,
数十年来 自从开始一英里跑计时以来
no one broke the four minute barrier.
没有人突破四分钟界限
It was considered impossible.
那被认为是不可能的
And on the 6th of May, Roger Bannister does it.
但在5月6日 Roger Bannister特做到了
Six weeks later, John Landy, the Australian runner,
六周后 澳大利亚跑手John Landy
runs the mile in 3 minutes 57.9 seconds.
一英里跑了3分57.9秒
The following year, 1955,
第二年 1955年
37 runners ran the mile in under 4 minutes.
37名跑手在四分钟内跑完一英里
1956, over 300 runners break the 4 minute barrier.
1956年 超过三百名跑手突破四分钟界限
Now what happened?
这是怎么回事?
Was it that somebody started to train harder?
运动员们更加努力训练?
Of course not.
当然不是
Was it new technologies, new shoes?
是有了新的技术 新的鞋子?
It wasn't. It was the mind.
不是 是信念
Look how powerful the mind is.
信念是多么强大
It wasn't the fact that they were running that time
不是因为跑到那个时间
and they say "Oops! We are over the speed limit!
就说"不好 超过速度极限了
Let's slow down a little bit."
放慢速度吧"
Not at all! They were trying their hardest,
根本不是那样 他们尽了最大努力
their utmost.
最大可能
And yet, their subconscious mind limited them,
然而他们的潜意识限制了他们
prevented them from breaking that barrier
阻止他们突破界限
that happened to be not a physical barrier as doctors,
那不是医生
physiologists and scientists had claimed.
生理学家和科学家们声称的身体界限
It was a mental barrier.
而是心理界限
And what Roger Bannister did was break down the fort,
Roger Bannister攻破了那个要塞
the mental psychological fort.
意志和心理上的要塞
Beliefs are self-fulfilling prophecies.
信念即自我实现预言
Very often they determine how we perform,
它们经常决定我们的表现
how well or how poorly we perform.
我们表现的多好或多糟
They often determine how good or not so good our relationships are.
经常决定我们的人际关系有多好或不那么好
They are the No. 1 predictor of life success as well as wellbeing,
它们是人生成功和幸福的头号预言
as we'll talk about.
我们将会谈到
So what we are going to talk about today and next time
今天和下节课我们要谈的是
is how beliefs shape reality.
信念如何形成现实
How it works?
它如何发挥作用?
What is the mechanism, the science behind the power of the mind?
信念力量背后的机制和科学是什么?
Because in many ways, this sounds like mysticism.
因为在很多方面 这听上去像神秘主义
And part of it is mystical-- still not understandable--
一部分是很神秘 仍无法理解
but we are going to talk about as much as we know--
但我们会谈到我们所知的
why it works and how it works.
信念为什么会起作用及如何起作用
There is unfortunately a lot of misunderstanding about optimism.
可惜 人们对乐观主义有很多误解
Because the self-help movement in many ways
因为自助运动在很多方面
is about telling us how it's all about the power of the mind,
是在告诉我们信念力量是怎么回事
talk about "Think and grow rich", the book;
提到《思考致富》那本书
we'll talk about the secrets
我们会讨论各种秘密
which is about creating our reality through our thoughts.
它们如何通过思想创造现实
And there's some truth to these-- but only some truth.
其中有些是事实 但仅是部分
We are going to bridge Ivory tower and Main Street,
我们将连通象牙塔和主街
and show the science and also the danger behind that belief.
说明那个信仰背后的科学和危险
Most importantly, how do we apply?
最重要的是如何应用?
How do we enhance the belief in ourselves
如何加强我们的信念
if there's such high correlation
如果真有这么紧密的关联
and there's a very high correlation
如果希望
and predictive power to a sense of hope,
乐观主义和信念真的
to a sense of optimism, to beliefs.
有着非常紧密的关联和预测力
If they so much determine our outcome,
如果它们决定我们的产出
in the athletic field,
无论在体育场上
in the workplace, in a relationship--
还是在工作地点 在人际关系上
if it matters so much, then how can we raise our beliefs?
如果它如此重要 那么该如何加强信念？
And we'll talk about work by Bandura on self-efficacy,
我们会谈到Bandura对自我效能的研究
or by Nathaniel Branden on self-esteem.
谈到Nathaniel Branden对自尊的研究
How we can make a dream into reality--
如何才能将梦想变成现实
whether it's political dream--
可以是政治梦想
we'll talk about Martin Luther King's dream approach-
我们将谈到马丁路德金的"梦想法"
how he did it and what he did;
他是如何做到 做了什么
or a personal dream,
也可以是个人梦想
where we'll talk about the work of Herbert Benson as well as Bandura.
我们会谈到Herbert Benson和Bandura
Once again, the Buddha,
再一次引用佛的话
"We are what we think.
"境随心转
All that we are arises with our thoughts.
全由意念升起
With our thoughts, we make our world."
我们的念头造就了世界"
Again, this was a claim made thousands of years ago.
这是几千年前的一个主张
What I want to do now
现在我要做的
is focus on the scientific foundation of this claim.
是专注于这个主张的科学基础
And I'll start by talking about Pygmalion in the classroom.
我会从皮格马利翁开始讲起
The source of the word, Pygmalion is ancient Greece.
"Pygmalion"是古希腊语
Pygmalion was a sculptor.
皮格马利翁是个雕刻家
And what he did was when he came of age looking for his ideal woman.
成年后他开始寻找理想中的女人
He wanted to get married.
他想结婚
So he went and looked around Athens where he lived;
他在雅典城里寻找
he looked around the all of Greece;
找遍整个希腊
he looked around the Greek Empire;
找遍整个希腊帝国
he looked beyond the Greek Empire, looking for his ideal woman--
去希腊帝国以外寻找 寻找他理想中的女人
a woman whom he could marry.
一个能和他结婚的女人
And he couldn't find her,
但没有找到
no matter where he looked.
不论去哪里找
I mean it's understandable--
这是可以理解的
this was before 1879 which was when Red Cliff was founded,
那是1879年之前 雷德克利夫学院还没成立
and long before Harvard became co-ed.
远在哈佛成为男女合校之前
So he couldn't find his ideal woman and he went back to Athens.
他找不到理想中的女人 于是他返回雅典
And he said to himself.
他对自己说
"Well, instead of finding that ideal woman,
"我不再寻找理想中的女人
I will create a sculpture"-- as he was a sculptor,
我要雕刻一座雕像"因为他是雕刻家
"I will create a sculpture in her image."
"我会以她的形象雕刻一座雕像"
And he created that sculpture.
他雕刻出那座雕像
And when he looked at her,
当他看着她时
he was so overwhelmed with emotion and sadness
他被激动之情和悲伤淹没
that he couldn't find her,
因为他找不到她
that he began to cry.
于是他开始哭泣
And then Zeus, Athena and especially Aphrodite,
宙斯 雅典娜 特别是阿芙罗狄蒂
looking down on him, took mercy and brought the statue to life.
俯视他 深感同情 于是把雕像变活
And of course, they lived happily ever after.
当然他们幸福地生活下去
So this is the source of the word, Pygmalion.
这是这个词的由来
Pygmalion was then taken by George Bernard Shaw,
然后萧伯纳借助这个词
who created a play based on a similar idea
创作了一部情节类似的戏剧
which was made into a musical, "My Fair Lady".
后来被改编成音乐剧《窈窕淑女》
The idea here is how Higgins,
说的是Higgins
doctor, linguist,
一位博士 语言学家
took a flower girl and molded her in the sense into being royalty.
如何把一个卖花女塑造成贵族
What of course happened through the story
当然故事讲完时
was that she molded him more and transformed him.
是她塑造了他 改变了他
Fascinating story and very important story at the time.
非常精彩的故事 当时很重要的故事
Because it challenged the whole class system,
因为它挑战了整个阶级体系
that people are born into a certain place and cannot--
人生来就有阶级 不能
and should not-- be moved.
也不应该被改变
So a very important play at that time, as well as today.
在当时是很重要的戏剧 今天也是如此
About Pygmalion and people can be changed,
皮格马利翁和人是可以被改变
can be transformed.
被改造的
In the 1960s,
1960年代
Robert Rosenthal who was the head of our department for many years--
Robert Rosenthal曾在本系担任多年主任
he's now in UC Riverside--
现在就职加州大学河滨分校
took this idea of Pygmalion and applied it in the classroom.
把皮格马利翁的思想应用于课堂
Here is what he did. Rosenthal went into a group of random schools.
他是这么做的 Rosenthal随便走进几间学校
And what he did there was went to the students,
去到学生中间
had them take a test
让他们接受一次测验
and then go to their teachers after and tell the teachers,
然后去找他们的老师并告诉他们
"Your students just took a new test that was devised--
"你们的学生刚接受了一个新测试
a new academic test which is called "the fast spurters' test".
一种新的学业测试 叫作快速迸发者测试"
What that means is that we identify students
测试能让我们找出
who are going to take a big leap,
将在新学年在学业上
intellectual leap forward in this coming year,
取得巨大进步的学生
a spurt forward in this coming year.
在新学年取得巨大进步
In other words, what he was saying--
换言之 他的意思是
it identifies students with highest potential.
测试找出最有潜力的学生
And what he found then was when he told these students--
他发现…
the teachers-- what he told these teachers was that
他对这些老师说的是
"it is just not a FYI-- you cannot tell the students this.
"这只是仅供参考 不能向学生透露
We don't want any discrimination in your school,
我们不希望学校有歧视行为
but just so you know, these are your fast spurters.
只是让你们知道 这些学生有巨大潜力
It's a new test, newly devised.
这是一项新发明的测试
Just so you know." Unbeknownst to the teachers,
只有你们知道就好"老师们不知道的是
the actual test which was given to those students
对学生进行的测试
was a regular off-the-shelf IQ test.
只是普通的现成的智商测试
Also unbeknownst to the teachers was these students names,
老师们也不知道这些所谓的
who were deemed "the fast spurters"/"high potential students",
"快速迸发者"或者潜力巨大的学生
were literally randomly picked out from a hat.
都是从一个帽子抓阄抓出来的
So there were regular students,
他们都是普通学生
like all other students,
和别的学生没有区别
but the teachers thought they were "fast spurters".
但老师们以为他们有巨大潜力
Robert Rosenthal leaves the school,
Robert Rosenthal离开学校
comes back in the end of the year.
学年结束时再回来
And here's what he finds-- he looks at their English scores:
他发现 他查看他们的英语成绩
the "fast spurters" improved significantly
"快速迸发"学生有明显进步
more than any of the other students.
比任何学生的进步都快
He looked at their maths scores,
他查看他们的数学成绩
because English is not really objective
因为英语不够客观
and you know maybe it was the teachers
也许是老师们
who thought they were better than they were really.
觉得某些学生英语更好
So he looked at their maths, their objective scores.
于是他查看他们的数学 客观的成绩
These students improved significantly
这些学生也有明显进步
more than any of the other students.
比其他任何学生的进步都大
But here is the clincher:
接下来才是有决定性的结果
Robert Rosenthal administered once again an IQ test
Robert Rosenthal又对所有学生
for all the students.
进行了一次智商测试
And what he found was the students who were labeled--
他发现被标签为
randomly so, but who were labeled--
被随机地标签为"快速迸发"的学生
"fast spurters", their IQ increased significantly over the year
智商在一年间有很大增加
and maintained that increase in a longitudinal study.
而且在长期研究中保持着增加
Now this is my bog I mean:
这让人不解
IQ is supposed to be in your intelligent quotient
智商
that you are born with!
本来是生而有之的
It's immutable.
它是恒定的
It doesn't change from the day you were born to the day you die--
从出生到死亡时都不会改变
or so they thought.
或者说他们这样认为
It changed significantly just based the belief
但它却因为
that the teacher had in her/his students.
老师对学生的信念而改变
Belief as self-fulfilling prophecies.
信念即自我实现预言
What happened in the study?
这项研究说明了什么？
Was it that the teachers were fooled?
老师们被骗了吗？
And suddenly were made to see an illusion? No.
突然产生幻象? 不是的
It was that they were alluded before.
是因为他们之前被欺骗
and the illusion was that they didn't see
幻象是他们看不到
what is right in front of their very eyes,
就在他们眼前的东西
which is the potential inherent in every single student.
即每个学生都有潜力
And then Robert Rosenthal comes and fools them in a sense,
Robert Rosenthal来到 可以说是骗了他们
but "fools" them into seeing what has been there all along.
"骗"他们注意到一直在眼前的东西
Before Rosenthal, they didn't see children on the bus.
在那之前 他们没注意到车上的孩子
So to speak.
可以这么说
After that, they suddenly in some children
之后 突然他们在一些孩子身上
saw the potential that was there all along.
看到一直都有的潜力
And they appreciated that potential and that potential appreciated.
他们欣赏那种潜力 潜力得到升值
They watered, they shed a light to it
他们灌溉 播撒阳光
and the seed germinated and grew.
种子开始发芽生长
This is exactly what Marva Collins does day in and day out in school.
这正是Marva Collins每天在学校里做的事
She seed the potential that is there;
她看到存在的潜力
she's not even inventing something.
她不是发明家
She's not detached from reality.
没有脱离现实
It's rather the people who don't see the potential in other people
是人们看不到他人身上的潜力
as well as in themselves as we'll discuss.
也看不到自己身上的潜力 我们会讨论到
They are not seeing the full reality.
他们没有看到整个现实
They are only seeing part of it.
只看到一部分
They are completely missing the children on the bus.
完全无视车上的孩子们
And we know how easy it is to miss part of reality,
我们知道无视一部分现实是多么容易
even they are right in front of our very eyes.
就算他们就在我们眼前
Or it often takes a question--
经常需要被问及
it takes on the quest and we miss what we have seen before,
问及我们之前忽略了什么
whether it was research with at-risk population,
不论是对风险人口的研究
whether it was the geometric shapes,
或者是人口结构
whether it was asking only the negative questions
或者只是对我们的
about our relationship or about ourselves,
人际关系和自己提出负面问题
or whether it's not seeing the potential
或者没有看到
that exist in just about all kids.
每个孩子身上都有的潜力
If only we see it.
如果我们看到它
And if we see it,
只要我们看到它
appreciate it, we water it,
欣赏它 灌溉它
we shed a light to it,
播撒阳光
and it appreciates, it grows.
它就会感恩 成长
So what Rosenthal did was simply shift their attention to something
Rosenthal做的只是将他们注意力
that was there all along.
转移到一直在那里的东西上
Same in the workplace.
在工作场所也是如此
Replicated hundreds, thousands of times--
几百几千次地重复着
the Pygmalion effect.
皮格马利翁效应
It was replicated in a workplace
曾在一个工作场所里重演过
where leaders are told or managers are told "these are your top,
主管或经理被告知 这些是
highest potential employees".
极有潜力的员工
And these employees, again, randomly picked,
那些员工也是随机挑出的
actually became the highest potential employees.
但真的变成最有潜力的员工
And they succeeded much more.
并取得更大成功
Retention went up for them; performance went up;
他们的保持力增加 工作表现出色
they were more likely to advance in their organization
在公司更有可能被升职
and stay in their organization.
并留在公司里
Just as result of expectation.
这都只是期望产生的结果
The source of works of the other way,
角色调换后结结果一样
Jamison, back in 1997, this fascinating study,
Jamison在1997年做了一项很有趣的研究
where what she said was let's see if it works the other way.
她想知道角色调换后是否有相同结果
So she went to two classes that were taught by the same teacher,
她去到由同一名老师负责的两个班
and before the classes were started,
开始上课之前
told just one of the classes
只告诉一个班
that this teacher was ranked extremely highly
这位老师受到
by other students before,
从前学生的极大好评
that they, as professional psychologists rated
他们作为心理学家
that teacher as extremely high.
给这名老师极高的评价
And they left them.
然后他们离开两个班
What happened by the end of the year?
学年结束时 情况如何？
First of all, the teacher was rated higher
首先 干预组给这名老师的评价
by the intervention group than by the control group.
高于对照组
But also, the students put in actually more time
而且学生对课业
into the class and they outperformed the control group.
付出更多时间 成绩比对照组好
Because they believed--
因为他们相信
they were made to believe that
他们被欺骗相信
the teacher was better that supposedly he/she were.
这位老师的水平比实际情况高
In other words, they saw the potent6ial in the teacher.
换言之 学生看到老师身上的潜力
They performed-- not only the teacher;
学生们表现得…与老师无关
the teacher did perform better--
老师没有更好的表现
but the students actually performed better
但学生表现得更好了
when they had high expectations,
当他们有更高的期望时
when they believed in their teachers.
当他们相信自己的老师时
So if you want to do well in 1504--
如果各位想学好1504这门课
you'll know what you need to do, right?
你们知道该怎么做了 是吗？
It works-- beliefs as self-fulfilling prophecies.
真得管用 信念即自我完成预言
We create our reality. Goethe,
我们创造我们的现实 歌德说过
"Treat a man as he is and he will remain as he is.
"人是怎样便怎样待他 他便还是那样的人
Treat a man as he can and should be,
一个人能够或应该怎样便怎样待他
and he shall become as he can and  should be."
他便会成为能够怎样或是应当怎样的人"
I want to move on now to a related topic,
现在我想谈一个相关话题
one that is very important for psychologist
它对心理学家很重要
but also for you to apply in your life.
对生活应用也很重要
And that is the importance of situation we create
那就是我们创造的情境
or that is created for us.
或为我们创造的情境的重要性
In many ways, psychologist--
在很多方面 心理学家
social psychologist for sure--
肯定地说是社会心理学家
was sponged by a series of research
都会被在情境之下完成的
that was done on the power of the situation,
一系列研究所影响
but it was mostly the negative power of the situation.
但多数是消极的情境
Those of you taken psych 1, those of you haven't,
修读或没修读过初级心理学的
may have heard of the "Asch Conformity Experiment",
可能都听说过"阿施从众心理实验"
where people conformed to the idea of the group.
个体对群体存在从众现象
Or many of you probably heard
很多同学可能听说过
of Milgram's "The obedience to authority".
Milgram的"权力服从"
If you haven't heard about them,
如果没听说过
I am not going to go in depth here,
我不会在这里深入介绍
read about it. Just Google it.
阅读了解一下 去网上找一下
Some of the most important fascinating studies
两者都是心理学领域
in the field of psychology where a person off the street
最精彩的研究 在街上随便找个人
was told by an experimenter to shock another person,
在实验者的指示去电击另一个人
even to the point where the other person is screaming to stop.
甚至电击到另一个人尖叫恳求停止
And because the experimenters were saying the experiment must go on
因为实验者说实验必须进行下去
and very often had a white cloak like doctors or experimenters--
而且实验者经常穿着一件白大褂
a cloak around them.
就像医生或者实验者
Because they said the experiment must go on,
因为他们说实验必须进行下去
very often, people went--
经常的 人们会
most people, Americans went on and shocked that person,
多数人 美国人都会继续电击那个人
even to the point of the other person whimpering
甚至电击到另一个人哭泣
and begging to be let out,
恳求放他出去
simply because of the word,
仅仅是因为那一句
"the experiment must go on".
"实验必须进行下去"
The power of the situation, obedience to authority--
情境的力量 对权力的服从
this was done in order to show how something like the Holocaust
这项研究的目的是为了证明
could only happen in Germany;
为什么大屠杀只发生在德国
how people are more likely to be obedient to authority
那里的人更容易服从权力
and what they found globally, worldwide,
他们发现全世界的人
people have the tendency to be obedient to authority,
都倾向服从权力
whether it was in United States or in Germany.
不论是在美国还是德国
Around the world.
全世界都是如何
Same replicated. The power of the situation.
如出一辙 情境的力量
Philip Zimbardo's Prison Experiment.
Philip Zimbardo的监狱实验
This was done at Stanford, where they did was taking--
在斯坦福进行 他们做的是
again, read about it if you haven't;
没读过的找来读
I am not going to go in depth here--
我不会深入介绍
where they took people off the street
他们从街上随便找来一些人
and had them play the role of either the prison warden,
分别扮演典狱长
the guard or the prisoner.
狱警和犯人
And the experiment was supposed to go on for two weeks
这项实验预计进行两周
to show what entering a role does.
证明进入角色的效果
And what they found was after a week,
一周后 他们发现
the experiment had to be stopped.
实验必须终止
Because the wardens-- people off the street, randomly divided-
因为随意找来的 随机分配的典狱长们
were becoming so oppressive.
变得非常残暴
They humiliated the prisoners
他们侮辱犯人
who got into their position of being humiliated,
进入犯人角色的人受到侮辱
just like prisoners often felt.
就像犯人经常感受到的侮辱
This explains Abu Ghraib.
这解释了Abu Ghraib监狱丑闻
You know, current phenomenon--
时事现象
what happened in the Iraqi prisons,
伊拉克战俘的遭遇
of how people off the street enter the role--
随便一个人一旦进入角色
they entered the role so much
他们进入得太深
that Zimbardo had to stop the experiment after one week.
Zimbardo不得不在一周后终止实验
Go on YouTube and watch the video about this mind-boggling stuff.
可以去视频网站上看到
So this is only important,
这是很重要的
good to know,important to know, but not enough.
知道很好 知道很重要 但不够
Because the situation is so powerful,
因为情境如此强大
why just emphasize the negative?
为什么只强调消极的东西？
Why not think about creating positive situations
为什么不创造积极的环境
that will help us lead happier, more moral lives?
让我们获得更快乐更讲道德的生活?
And this has, just like a lot of positive psychological approaches,
正像很多积极心理方法一样
has been ignored with a ratio 21 to 1.
被21比1的比率忽视
So let me share with you just a couple of studies in this area.
我要和大家分享这个领域的两项研究
Both of them done by our very own Ellen Langer.
两项研究都由本校的Ellen Langer完成
This, by the way, is the study that I am going to share now
顺便说一句 我现在要讲到的这项研究
is going to be backbone of a movie coming out about Professor Langer--
是即将推出的Langer教授记录片的主干
the person who's going to play Ellen Langer--
扮演Ellen Langer的演员 Langer是
she's the first female tenure professor in the psychology department
心理学系的第一位女性终身教授
the person who's going to play Ellen Langer is Jennifer Aniston.
扮演Ellen Langer的是詹妮弗安妮斯顿
And the movie is coming out, hopefully in a year,
电影有望在一年后上映
but it's about the experiment that I am going to share with you now.
但电影讲的是我要谈到的这项实验
So this was done in 1979.
实验在1979年进行
Here was what Langer did.
Langer的实验是
What she did was take men
她找来
who were above 75 years old and sent them to a retreat,
75岁以上的男人 把他们送去一座别墅
which was a 1959 retreat, meaning--
那是间以1959为主题的别墅
even though it was 1979--
虽然实验在1979年进行
the music was from 1959,
音乐来自1959年
the magazines that they read that were all around were 1959,
他们读的杂志都是1959年前后的
the daily newspapers were 1959--
日报是1959年的
everything was 1959.
所有的一切都是1959年的
Even they had to go into a role,
就算他们要进入角色
just like in Zimbardo,
和Zimbardo的实验一样
they had to play their role of 1959 as if they were 20 years younger.
要扮演1959年时的角色 仿佛年轻了20岁
Now of course, it was a psychological experiment,
这是个心理学实验
they had all these different measures, taken before/after.
在实验前后进行各种测量
And here is what they found.
他们发现
One week. Retreat.
在别墅待了一周
At the end of the week,
在一周结束时
both mental and biological age decreased.
心理和生理年纪都减小了
For example, they became more flexible in tests.
比如 他们在各项测试中变得更灵活
They became stronger-- their grasp, their legs,
他们变得更强壮 他们手掌 双腿
their bodies became stronger.
身体都变得更强壮
Their memory improved significantly,
他们的记忆力有明显改善
so their intelligence level as taking
他们的智力水平
by tests before and after compared to control group
在实验前后进行测试 再与对照组相比
improved significantly after a single week.
在仅仅一周后就有明显改进
She measured the distance between the bones in the finger,
她测量指骨间的距离
because when we get older, the space becomes smaller--
人越老 骨骼间空隙变得越小
they become tighter.
指骨变得更紧
The length after a week, increased in their fingers.
一周后 他们的手指变长
They became happier.
他们变得更快乐
They became more self-sufficient,
变得更加自立
less dependent on other people as rated by themselves
更少依懒他们 不论是他们自己
and as rated by their family members.
还是家庭成员的评估都是如此
They became healthier.
他们变得更健康
Their eyesight and hearing improved significantly
他们的视力和听觉有明显改善
in as little as a week.
在短短一周时间内
Just because they entered a powerful, positive situation,
就是因为他们进入了强大的积极的情境
which goes against a lot of the stereotypes
与在外面世界遭遇的
and prejudices that they encountered in the outside world.
典型情况和偏见不同
So just by "acting" a certain role,
仅仅通过"扮演"某个角色
they became that role just like Zimbardo's prisoners
他们变成那个角色 正如Zimbardo的犯人
became their role in as little as a week.
在短短一周内真的变成犯人
Another study that she did--
她的另一项研究
and this is a report in her book,
她在书中有叙述
"Mindfulness", which I highly recommend.
《念》 我强烈推荐这本书
She took in and tested people's eyesight.
她测量人们的视力
And she gave them a normal eyesight chart,
给他们一幅普通的视力表
measured them, wrote down their performance.
测量他们的视力 记录结果
And then she took the exact same people--
然后她把让同一群人
this time, put them in a pilot overalls
这次让他们穿上飞行服
and at the same time put them in a flight simulator
同时让他们坐进飞行模拟器
and showed them the exact same the eye chart.
然后给他们看完全相同的视力表
Same distance, same eye chart,
相同的距离 相同的视力表
the only difference being they're sitting in a flight simulator
唯一的不同是 他们坐在
and they were wearing pilot overalls.
飞行模拟器里 穿着飞行服
They were sitting there, looking at the eye chart.
他们坐在那里看视力表
And again, she ran the eye test.
然后她又进行了一次视力测试
40% of participants eyesight improved significantly,
40%的参与者的视力有明显改善
as a result of just changing the situation.
仅仅是在改变情境的情况下
Same distance, same chart, same everything.
相同的距离 相同的表 什么都一样
Different situation.
只是情境不同
The question is how do we create a positive situation.
问题是我们如何创造积极情境
How can we create a situation that improves us with the role.
如何创造一个利用角色自我改进的情境
And I want to share with you couple of studies--
我想介绍两个研究
I'll share one study and then another later-- about the environment.
先说第一个再说第二个 关于环境
First of all, the work of Barge,
首先是Barge的研究
priming is when we have subconscious or conscious priming.
影射分为潜意识和有意识影射
For example, you are looking at a screen
比如你看着一个屏幕
and for just a few milliseconds, a word appears.
在几毫秒内闪过一个词
And the word primes you.
这个词让你有了准备
There is a lot of research on
有很多关于如何利用
how we can prime your negatively with stereotypes for example,
典型消极情况进行影射的研究 比如
with prejudices.
使用偏见
Or positively-- but not enough from positively.
或者积极的 但对积极影射的研究不够
So here's a story done by Barge.
Barge做了下面的实验
He primed people with words associated with old.
他用与"老"有关的词影射人
So for example, word such as old,
比如"老"这个词
word such as stick,
"拐杖"
word such as Florida--
"佛罗里达"
that's one of the words he primed people with.
他用这个词影射人们
So he primed people with "old" words.
他用与老有关的词影射人们
And then he had them take a comparative and control group
然后他对比他们和对照组的
an intelligence test and a memory test.
智力和记忆力测试结果
The memory of the people who were primed with "old" words.
用与"老"相关的词影射过的人的记忆力
They performed the worst than the control group.
他们的表现比对照组差
Second, he looked at these people
第二 他观察这些人
and measured how fast they walk from
记录他们从实验地点
where their experiment was to the elevator.
走到电梯的时间
And also had blind evaluators--
还找来盲测员
people who didn't know which condition they were in,
那些不了解情况的人
evaluate how they were walking.
评估他们的走路
So the people who were primed with old actually walked
用"老"影射过的人行走起来
more stoop than the other people.
真得比其他人更弯腰驼背
And they walk significantly slower toward the elevator,
走向电梯的速度明显慢
not knowing that they were primed with old words.
虽然不知道自己被与"老"相关的字影射过
They walk slower toward the elevator.,
但他们走向电梯的速度
then the people who were not primed with these old words,
比没有受到影响的人慢
subconscious completely.
完全是潜意识的
And then they did something priming people with words
然后他们用与"成就"相关的词
related to an achievement.
影射人们
The people who were primed,
受到影射的人
subconsciously with words related to achievement,
用与"成就"有关的词进行潜意识影射的人
did better on tests than control group.
测试结果比对照组好
Their memory improved,
他们的记忆力得到改进
and they persisted more on difficult tasks.
面对困难任务时更有持久力
And the question is-- the thing we'll talk about next time--
问题是…下次课我会谈到的是
is how can we create consciously
如何创造有意识的
and subconsciously a positive environment
和潜意识的积极环境
where we actually can take out the most moral,
让我们带出最有道德
most successful self, to appreciate that self,
最成功的自我 并且去欣赏那个自我
to help the environment bring out the best in us.
帮助环境带出最杰出的自己
Next time.
下堂课见